Guide to the Everett Cherrington Hughes Papers 1922-1982
University of Chicago Library
- Series V: French Canada Studies
  - Subseries 1: General
    - Colleges classique, Canadian newspaper clippings, 1965 (Box 117, Folder 12)
    - Coops organizations for collective action, Canadian newspaper clippings, 1965 (Box 117, Folder 13)
    - Economic policies and conditions, Canadian newspaper clippings, 1965 (Box 117, Folder 14)
    - Extremism, Canadian newspaper clippings, 1965 (Box 117, Folder 15)
    - FrËre Lahaie et Hitler, Canadian newspaper clippings, 1965 (Box 117, Folder 16)
    - Immigration and emigration, Canadian newspaper clippings, 1965 (Box 117, Folder 17)
    - Labor, syndicalism, Canadian newspaper clippings, 1965 (Box 117, Folder 18)
    - Laicism vs. clericalism, Canadian newspaper clippings, 1965 (Box 117, Folder 19)
    - L'...tat du Quebec, proposals and debates concerning separatism, Canadian newspaper clippings, 1965 (Box 117, Folder 20)
    - May 24 and other street demonstrations, violence, newspaper clippings, 1965 (Box 117, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous, newspaper clippings, 1965 (Box 117, Folder 22)
    - Politics, Canadian newspaper clippings, 1965 (Box 117, Folder 23)
    - St. Jean Baptiste Society, Canadian newspaper clippings, 1965 (Box 117, Folder 24)
    - Ties with French areas abroad, newspaper clippings, 1965 (Box 117, Folder 25)
    - Use of symbols, flag, Queen, Canadian newspaper clippings, 1965 (Box 117, Folder 26)
    - French Canada monograph, notes, summer 1967 (Box 117, Folder 27)
    - de Gaulle visit to Canada, notes on newspaper accounts, 1967 (Box 117, Folder 28)
    - Higher and professional education, newspaper clippings, notes, memoranda, 1965-1967 (Box 118, Folder 1)
    - Premier RenÈ LÈvesque, newspaper clippings, handbill, 1976, 1978 (Box 118, Folder 2)
    - Carlton University, Ottawa, seminar, "Action Catholique and Nationalism," March 17, 1978 (Box 118, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1925, 1963-1967 (Box 118, Folder 4)
    - Book list, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 5)
    - "...cole des Sciences Sociales," manuscript, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 6)
    - Jacques Dofny et Muriel Garon-Audy, "MobilitÈs professionnelles au QuÈbec," Sociologie et SociÈtÈs, reprint, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 7)
    - Symbols of Canada, mimeograph, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 8)
    - memoranda, 1963 (Box 118, Folder 9)
    - memoranda, 1964 (Box 118, Folder 10)
    - memoranda, 1965 (Box 118, Folder 11)
    - memoranda, 1966 (Box 118, Folder 12)
    - memoranda, 1967 (Box 118, Folder 13)
    - memoranda, 1968 (Box 118, Folder 14)
    - memoranda, 1970 (Box 118, Folder 15)
    - memoranda, Canada crisis, kidnapping, newspaper clippings, 1970 (Box 118, Folder 16)
    - memoranda, 1971 (Box 118, Folder 17)
    - memoranda, RenÈ LÈvesque, 1972 (Box 118, Folder 18)
    - memoranda, 1974 (Box 118, Folder 19)
    - memoranda, 1977 (Box 118, Folder 20)
    - memoranda, review of Dangerous Delusions by Douglas H. Fullerton, 1978 (Box 118, Folder 21)
    - memoranda, 1979 (Box 118, Folder 22)
    - memoranda, 1980 (Box 118, Folder 23)
  - Subseries 2: Study of the Careers and Career Aspirations of Young Canadians, 1965
    - Sub-subseries 1: Administration
      - Proposals of those preparing briefs for the Royal Commission on Bilingualism and Biculturalism, 1963 (Box 119, Folder 1)
      - Hughes proposals, 1963-1965 (Box 119, Folder 2)
      - Royal Commission on Bilingualism and Biculturalism, public documents, reports, 1963-1964 (Box 119, Folder 3-4)
      - Budget, 1965 (Box 119, Folder 5)
      - Interim report, correspondence, April 21, 1965 (Box 119, Folder 6)
      - Brief report of Project on Careers, September 8, 1965 (Box 119, Folder 7)
      - "Preliminary memorandum submitted to the research division of the Royal Commission on Bilingualism and Biculturalism in February, 1966," mimeograph (Box 119, Folder 8)
      - "Career Patterns of Young Montrealers in Certain White-Collar Occupations," final report to the Royal Commission on Bilingualism and Biculturalism, draft, 1966 (Box 119, Folder 9)
      - "Career Patterns of Young Montrealers in Certain White-Collar Occupations," final report to the Royal Commission on Bilingualism and Biculturalism, original, Introduction to Chapter 5, July 1966 (Box 119, Folder 10)
      - "Career Patterns of Young Montrealers in Certain White-Collar Occupations," final report to the Royal Commission on Bilingualism and Biculturalism, Chapter 7 to Conclusion, July 1966 (Box 119, Folder 11)
      - "Career Patterns of Young Montrealers in Certain White-Collar Occupations," final report to the Royal Commission on Bilingualism and Biculturalism, June 1966 (Box 119, Folder 12)
      - Oliver, Michael, "Research Programme of the Royal Commission on Bilingualism and Biculturalism," Gray lecture, March 2, 1965 (Box 120, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, personnel for the project, 1963-1965 (Box 120, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, McGill University, Laurier L. LaPierre, Aileen Ross, 1963-1965 (Box 120, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 120, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 120, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 120, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 120, Folder 7)
      - Hughes, research material, notes, memoranda, 1965 (Box 120, Folder 8-10)
      - Hughes, research material, notes, memoranda, 1966-1967, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 11)
      - Bibliography, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 12)
      - Chiasson, HÈlËne, correspondence, rÈsumÈ, 1964-1965 (Box 120, Folder 13)
      - Dermine, Anne-Marie, correspondence, reports, 1965-1967 (Box 120, Folder 14)
      - Filotas, George, correspondence, notes, 1965 (Box 120, Folder 15)
      - Gauthier, Pierre, correspondence, notes, reports, 1965-1966 (Box 120, Folder 16)
      - Lamontagne, Jacques, correspondence, notes, reports, 1965-1966 (Box 121, Folder 1)
      - Robert, Nicole, correspondence, notes, 1965 (Box 121, Folder 2)
      - Westley, Margaret, correspondence, reports, 1964-1967 (Box 121, Folder 3)
      - Williamson, Kenneth, correspondence, interview report, 1965 (Box 121, Folder 4)
      - Canadian census occupations, 1961 (Box 121, Folder 5)
      - General interview techniques and problems (Box 121, Folder 6)
      - Meetings of research team, May-July 1965 [French] (Box 121, Folder 7)
      - Tables, charts and forms (Box 121, Folder 8)
      - Letters for interviews [English] (Box 121, Folder 9)
      - Letters for interviews [French] (Box 121, Folder 10)
      - Sample interview and chart [English] (Box 121, Folder 11)
      - Sample interview and chart [French] (Box 121, Folder 12)
      - Instructions for interviewers, instructions for using life history chart [English] (Box 121, Folder 13)
      - Instructions for interviewers, instructions for using life history chart[French] (Box 121, Folder 14)
    - Sub-subseries 2: Research Data
      - Bell Telephone Company of Canada, "Eastern Region Language Skill, Non-Management," April 1965 (Box 121, Folder 15)
      - Bell Telephone Company of Canada, correspondence, lists of interviewees, notes, memoranda (Box 121, Folder 16)
      - Bell Telephone Company of Canada, interviews (Box 121, Folder 17-19)
      - Bell Telephone Company of Canada, reports by interviewers (Box 122, Folder 1)
      - Imperial Tobacco, correspondence, lists of interviewees, notes, memoranda, reports (Box 122, Folder 2)
      - Imperial Tobacco, interviews (Box 122, Folder 3-4)
      - McGill University, Graduate School of Nursing, correspondence, lists of interviewees, notes, memoranda, reports (Box 122, Folder 5)
      - McGill University, interviews (Box 122, Folder 6-7)
      - Medical professions, statistics, tables (Box 122, Folder 8)
      - Medical professions, correspondence, memoranda, notes, autobiographical profiles (Box 122, Folder 9)
      - Medical professions, interviews (Box 122, Folder 10)
      - Medical professions, interviews, reports (Box 123, Folder 1)
      - Bilingual secretaries, correspondence, lists of interviewees, notes, memoranda, reports (Box 123, Folder 2)
      - Bilingual secretaries, interviews (Box 123, Folder 3-4)
      - Creative workers of the mass media, correspondence, memoranda, reports, pilot interview (Box 123, Folder 5)
      - Creative workers of the mass media, interviews (Box 123, Folder 6-7)
      - Union officers studying at the Labor College, memoranda, lists of students, interviews (Box 123, Folder 8)
      - Union officers studying at the Labor College, interviews (Box 123, Folder 9)
      - Union officers studying at the Labor College, interviews (Box 124, Folder 1)
      - Careers of leaders of a social movement, La Jeunesse ...tudiante Catholique (J.E.C.), memoranda, notes, interviews, reports, list of interviewees (Box 124, Folder 2)
      - Careers of leaders of a social movement, interviews (Box 124, Folder 3)
      - Teachers, students of the Programme for B.A. for adults at UniversitÈ de MontrÈal, memoranda, notes, reports, lists of interviewees (Box 124, Folder 4)
      - Teachers, interviews (Box 124, Folder 5-6)
      - New professions, memoranda, notes, reports (Box 124, Folder 7)
      - New professions, interviews (Box 124, Folder 8-9)
      - MÈres de famille, correspondence, memoranda, interview, report (Box 124, Folder 10)
      - MËres de famille, interviews (Box 125, Folder 1)
      - Association d'hommes d'affaires et de professionnels, Tribune ...conomique et Sociale du QuÈbec (TESQ), interviews, report (Box 125, Folder 2)
      - Mouvements paraprofessionelles, interviews by Jacques Lamontagne (Box 125, Folder 3)
      - Reports by categories (Box 125, Folder 4)
      - Career pattern charts (Box 125, Folder 5-6)
      - Vital statistics of project (Box 125, Folder 7)
- Series VI: University of Kansas Medical and General Education Studies
  The Kansas City and University of Chicago connection was already established through the Kansas City Study of Adult Life. This work was done under the direction of Robert J. Havighurst and the University of Chicago's Committee on Human Development. It was supported by the Carnegie Corporation and Community Studies, Inc., a research body financed by several local trusts of Kansas City. Everett Hughes had become affiliated with the Committee on Human Development in the 1950s and he began talking to Dr. Dimond of the University of Kansas Medical School about a study of specialization in medical schools in 1952. The pilot study was underway by the fall of 1955 and was conducted by Howard S. Becker. Most of this team, Becker, Geer, and Hughes, moved directly into another study of undergraduates at the University of Kansas, and the final publication for this study was Making the Grade, 1968. Because the completion of one study was taking place while the other study was getting underway, and because the records of the two studies were inter-filed, it seemed appropriate to keep these groups together.
  Subseries VI has been divided into four subseries: (1) Administration, (2) Articles and Publications, (3) Research Data, and (4) Related Studies. All these subseries are arranged chronologically. Hughes supervised these studies for the most part long distance from both the University of Chicago and Brandeis University, so there is a wealth of reports and memoranda that fall into the category of correspondence. The correspondence with Community Studies Inc., which holds correspondence with both Howard S. Becker and Blanche Geer. Hughes did conduct interviews and manage the projects on site during some parts of 1959 and 1961. The rest of the field work on record in this collection was done by Howard S. Becker, Blanche Geer, Marsh Ray, and Rue Bucher.
  - Subseries 1: Administration
    - Medical sociology, reprints, 1935-1952 (Box 125, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, Carnegie Corporation of New York, 1958-1960 (Box 125, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, Carnegie Corporation of New York, project expenditures, 1960-1961 (Box 125, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, University of Kansas, Franklin D. Murphy, Chancellor, 1958 (Box 125, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, University of Kansas, George R. Waggoner, Dean, College of Arts and Sciences, 1958-1961 (Box 125, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, University of Kansas, Carroll D. Clark, Chairman, Department of Sociology, 1958-1961 (Box 125, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, Community Studies, Inc., memoranda, 1958-1961 (Box 126, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, primarily concerning funding, memoranda, 1956-1967 (Box 126, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, primarily concerning funding, memoranda, 1957-1959 (Box 126, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, primarily concerning funding, 1960 (Box 126, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, primarily concerning visits to Kansas, 1961 (Box 126, Folder 5)
    - Project proposals, initial meetings, 1952-1956 (Box 126, Folder 6)
    - Project Proposals, notes, manuscripts, 1957-1959 (Box 126, Folder 7)
    - Becker, Howard S., Blanche Geer, David Riesman, correspondence, memoranda, 1955-1957 (Box 126, Folder 8)
    - Becker, Howard S., Blanche Geer, David Riesman, correspondence, memoranda, 1958 (Box 126, Folder 9)
    - Geer, reports, 1959 (Box 126, Folder 10)
    - Becker, Geer, Hughes, correspondence, memoranda, 1961 (Box 126, Folder 11)
    - Hughes, miscellaneous notes and research material, 1957-1960 (Box 126, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 2: Articles and Publications
    - Becker, Howard S., "Some Notes on the Concept of Commitment," paper, Midwest Sociological Society, April 1959 (Box 127, Folder 1)
    - Becker, Howard S., "The Transmission of Social Science Results: The Case of the Kansas University Medical Faculty," confidential report, n.d. (Box 127, Folder 2)
    - Becker, Howard S., "Social-Class Variations in the Teacher-Pupil Relationship," n.d. (Box 127, Folder 3)
    - Becker, Geer, "A Method for Analyzing Group Perspectives from Field Work Data," rough draft, January 1959 (Box 127, Folder 4)
    - Becker, Geer, Hughes, "Student Culture and Academic Effort," n.d. (Box 127, Folder 5)
    - Becker, Geer, Ray, "Family and Campus," 1960 (Box 127, Folder 6)
    - Becker, "Grade Point Average and College Life," 1960 (Box 127, Folder 7)
    - Hughes, Stephens Lectures, galley proofs, notes, correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 127, Folder 8)
    - Hughes, "Stresses and Strains in a Medical School," paper, 1957 (Box 127, Folder 9)
    - Hughes, "General Ideas on the Medical Faculty," notes, paper, ca. 1959 (Box 127, Folder 10)
    - Becker, Geer, Hughes, Strauss, Boys in White, correspondence, 1960 (Box 127, Folder 11)
    - Becker, Geer, drafts, notes, 1960 (Box 127, Folder 12-13)
  - Subseries 3: Research Data
    - Faculty seminars, field reports, 1957 (Box 127, Folder 14)
    - Faculty seminars, field reports, 1957-1958 (Box 127, Folder 15)
    - Hughes, notes, 1955 (Box 127, Folder 16)
    - Hughes, "The Faculty," notes, related research material, ca. 1956-1957 (Box 127, Folder 17)
    - Hughes, faculty, notes, related research material, 1956-1959 (Box 127, Folder 18)
    - Hughes, faculty morale, memorandum, notes, reports, 1959 (Box 128, Folder 1)
    - Hughes, interview schedule, notes, 1956 (Box 128, Folder 2)
    - Hughes, faculty interviews, April 1956 (Box 128, Folder 3)
    - Hughes, faculty interviews, October-December 1956 (Box 128, Folder 4)
    - Hughes, faculty interviews, March-July 1957 (Box 128, Folder 5)
    - Hughes, faculty interviews, surgery, anesthesiology, urology, 1956 (Box 128, Folder 6)
    - Hughes, faculty interviews, otorhinolaringology, psychiatry, neurology, 1956-1957 (Box 128, Folder 7)
    - Hughes, faculty interviews, pediatrics, 1956-1957 (Box 128, Folder 8)
    - Hughes, faculty interviews, obstetrics and gynecology, 1956 (Box 128, Folder 9)
    - Hughes, faculty interviews, pathology, pharmacology, microbiology, 1956-1957 (Box 128, Folder 10)
    - Hughes, field notes, 1958 (Box 128, Folder 11)
    - Hughes, field notes, September-December 1959 (Box 128, Folder 12-13)
    - Hughes, field notes, 1960 (Box 128, Folder 14)
    - Hughes, field notes, 1961 (Box 128, Folder 15-16)
    - Hughes, field notes, 1962 (Box 129, Folder 1)
    - Bucher, Rue, faculty, medical specialties, field reports, ca. 1955-1957 (Box 129, Folder 2)
    - Becker, Geer, faculty interview, 1957 (Box 129, Folder 3)
    - Becker, Geer, Strauss, "Index to Field Notes for the Clinical Years," volume 1, 1955-1956 (Box 129, Folder 4)
    - Becker, Geer, Strauss, "Index to Field Notes for the Clinical Years," volume 2, 1956 (Box 129, Folder 5)
    - Becker, Howard S., field notes, January-April 1960 (Box 129, Folder 6)
    - Becker, Howard S., field notes, April-June 1960 (Box 129, Folder 7)
    - Becker, Howard S., field notes, September-October 1960 (Box 129, Folder 8)
    - Becker, Howard S., field notes, October-December 1960 (Box 129, Folder 9)
    - Becker, Howard S., field notes, January-February 1961 (Box 130, Folder 1)
    - Becker, Howard S., field notes, March-May 1961 (Box 130, Folder 2)
    - Becker, Howard S., field notes, April-May 1961 (Box 130, Folder 3)
    - Becker, Howard S., index to field notes, 1959-1961 (Box 130, Folder 4-6)
    - Geer, Blanche, memoranda, 1958-1962 (Box 130, Folder 7)
    - Geer, Blanche, field notes, 1959 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Geer, Blanche, field notes, January-September 1960 (Box 131, Folder 2)
    - Geer, Blanche, field notes, September-October 1960 (Box 131, Folder 3)
    - Geer, Blanche, field notes, October-November 1960 (Box 131, Folder 4)
    - Geer, Blanche, field notes, November-December 1960 (Box 131, Folder 5)
    - Geer, Blanche, field notes, January-February 1961 (Box 131, Folder 6)
    - Geer, Blanche, field notes, February-March 1961 (Box 131, Folder 7)
    - Geer, Blanche, field notes, March-April 1961 (Box 132, Folder 1)
    - Geer, Blanche, field notes, May-June 1961 (Box 132, Folder 2)
    - Geer, Blanche, index to field notes, 1959-1960 (Box 132, Folder 3-5)
    - Geer, Blanche, memoranda, tables, October 1961 (Box 132, Folder 6)
    - Ray, Marsh, field notes, January-March 1960 (Box 132, Folder 7)
    - Ray, Marsh, field notes, April-July 1960 (Box 132, Folder 8)
    - Ray, Marsh, field notes, July-October 1960 (Box 132, Folder 9)
    - Ray, Marsh, field notes, October-December 1960 (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Ray, Marsh, field notes, January-February 1961 (Box 133, Folder 2)
    - Ray, Marsh, field notes, March-May 1961 (Box 133, Folder 3)
    - Ray, Marsh, confidential index to field notes, 1959-1961 (Box 133, Folder 4)
    - Ray, Marsh, index to field notes, September 1959 (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Ray, Marsh, index to field notes, October 1959 (Box 133, Folder 6)
    - Ray, Marsh, index to field notes, November 1959 (Box 133, Folder 7)
    - Ray, Marsh, index to field notes, December 1959 (Box 133, Folder 8)
    - Ray, Marsh, index to field notes, January 1960 (Box 133, Folder 9)
    - Ray, Marsh, index to field notes, February 1960 (Box 133, Folder 10)
    - Ray, Marsh, index to field notes, March 1960 (Box 134, Folder 1)
    - Ray, Marsh, index to field notes, April 1960 (Box 134, Folder 2)
    - Ray, Marsh, index to field notes, May 1960 (Box 134, Folder 3)
    - Ray, Marsh, index to field notes, June, September 1960 (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Ray, Marsh, index to field notes, October 1960 (Box 134, Folder 5)
    - Hughes, Becker, Geer, field notes, memorandum, papers, 1964 (Box 134, Folder 6)
    - Miller, Stephen J., field notes, correspondence, memorandum, papers, 1964 (Box 134, Folder 7-9)
    - Miller, Stephen J., field notes, correspondence, memorandum, papers, 1964 (Box 135, Folder 1-3)
  - Subseries 4: Related Studies
    - National Opinion Research Center, "The Intern Looks at the Army, Report of an Exploratory Survey Conducted in 34 Hospitals," 1947 (Box 135, Folder 4)
    - National Opinion Research Center, "Studies in Medical Education," 1959 (Box 135, Folder 5)
    - Columbia University Project, correspondence, memoranda, 1954-1956 (Box 135, Folder 6)
    - New, Peter, "Student Cultures and Student Careers in Small, Non-elite Colleges," research proposal, 1959 (Box 135, Folder 7)
    - Riesman, David, and Christopher Jencks, "A Vignette of San Francisco State College, " 1960 (Box 135, Folder 8)
    - Medicine, papers, manuscripts, ca. 1955 (Box 135, Folder 9)
    - Education, papers, proposals, ca. 1959 (Box 135, Folder 10)
    - Papers, reprints, 1957-1961 (Box 135, Folder 11)
- Series VII: Helen MacGill Hughes (1903-1992)
  Helen MacGill graduated with a double degree in Economics and German from the University of British Columbia. On hearing a lecture by Winifred Raushenbush on Chinatown in Vancouver and then speaking with Robert Park, who persuaded her to come to the University of Chicago and study sociology under a Laura Spelman Rockefeller Fellowship, Ms. MacGill came to the University in 1925. Here she met and married Everett Hughes in 1927. Helen was able to complete her Ph.D. in 1937 under the direction of Robert Park. The next year Helen and Everett came back to the University of Chicago when Everett received an assistant professorship.
  World War II soon began and with the shortage of the usual male graduate students to fill the position of editorial assistant at the American Journal of Sociology, Herbert Blumer offered Helen Hughes the job. She worked as an editor for the American Journal of Sociology for 17 years from 1944 until 1961, when she and Everett moved to Boston for Everett to take a post at Brandeis University in 1961.
  The only substantive files of her work are from her editorship of a study, The Status of Women in Sociology, 1968-1972: Report to the American Sociological Association of the Ad Hoc Committee on the Status of Women in the Profession.
  Please refer to the Audio-Visual series to find a microfilmed manuscript of The Fantastic Lodge: The Autobiography of a Girl Addict. This monograph was published in 1961. Helen MacGill edited this work and Howard S. Becker made the recordings on which the text is based.
  - Vitae, bibliographies, 1975 (Box 136, Folder 1)
  - "Land Values as an Ecological Factor in the Community of South Chicago," University of Chicago, master's thesis, 1927 (Box 136, Folder 2)
  - "The Newspaper," Canadian newspaper clippings, notes, 1927-1928 (Box 136, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1930-1939 (Box 136, Folder 4)
  - Race relations, note, 1968 (Box 136, Folder 5)
  - "Eulogy for Margaret Park Redfield," manuscript, 1977 (Box 136, Folder 6)
  - Helen MacGill Hughes, ed. "The Status of Women in Sociology, 1968-1972," pamphlet, 1973 (Box 136, Folder 7)
  - Helen MacGill Hughes, ed. "The Status of Women in Sociology, 1968-1972," "Introduction," Chapter 1, draft, n.d. (Box 136, Folder 8)
  - Helen MacGill Hughes, ed. "The Status of Women in Sociology, 1968-1972," Chapter 2, draft, n.d. (Box 136, Folder 9)
  - Helen MacGill Hughes, ed. "The Status of Women in Sociology, 1968-1972," Chapter 3, draft, n.d. (Box 136, Folder 10)
  - Helen MacGill Hughes, ed. "The Status of Women in Sociology, 1968-1972," Chapter 4, draft, n.d. (Box 136, Folder 11)
  - Helen MacGill Hughes, ed. "The Status of Women in Sociology, 1968-1972," Chapters, 5, 7, References, draft, n.d. (Box 136, Folder 12)
  - Helen MacGill Hughes, ed. "The Status of Women in Sociology, 1968-1972," Chapter 6, draft, n.d. (Box 136, Folder 13)
  - Helen MacGill Hughes, ed. "The Status of Women in Sociology, 1968-1972," tables, n.d. (Box 137, Folder 1-2)
  - Helen MacGill Hughes, ed. "The Status of Women in Sociology, 1968-1972," full draft, n.d. (Box 137, Folder 3-4)
  - Helen MacGill Hughes, ed. "The Status of Women in Sociology, 1968-1972," correspondence, 1972 (Box 137, Folder 5)
  - Helen MacGill Hughes, ed. "The Status of Women in Sociology, 1968-1972," correspondence, 1973 (Box 137, Folder 6)
  - Other studies on women in academic fields, 1971-1972 (Box 137, Folder 7-8)